- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[cool jazz music]
[酷炫的爵士乐]
*
- * La-la la-la-la
la-la-la la-la-la la-la-la *
- * 啦啦啦啦啦
啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦*
Hmm, maybe I could use
a little music
嗯，也许我可以用
一点音乐
to make my work
even more fun.
使我的工作
更有趣。
[groans]
[呻吟]
Aha!
There you are!
啊哈！
你在那里！
Hi!
你好！
[rock music playing]
[摇滚乐演奏]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
- * Yeah, Kung Fu Rock
Kung Fu Rock *
- * 是的，功夫摇滚
功夫摇滚 *
* Kick off your socks,
get a clap on the chops *
*脱掉你的袜子，
拍拍排骨*
* Swing one, swing two,
smack down, pop! *
* 摇摆一，摇摆二，
一击落下，噗！ *
* That's how you do
the Kung Fu Rock *
* 这就是你要做的
功夫摇滚 *
- Hey, boss,
it says, "Closed.
- 嘿，老板，
它说：“关闭。
Feel free to slide money
under the door."
随意滑动金钱
在门下面。”
- Thank you, Professor Lonnie.
Here's a flash: I can read!
- 谢谢你，朗尼教授。
闪现：我能读书！
- Aw, man, I really wanted
to sink my teeth into something.
- 噢，伙计，我真的很想要
让我的牙齿陷入某事。
- Hey, there's somebody
in there.
- 嘿，有人
在那里。
*
- Look at that kid go.
- 看看那个孩子走了。
*
- Ow-wah!
- 哇哇！
- * Kung Fu Rock
- * 功夫摇滚
- What power!
- 什么力量！
- [fighting yells]
- What force!
- [战斗叫喊]
- 什么力量！
- What's for dinner?
- 晚餐吃什么？
- Clam it, Donnie.
- 闭上它，唐尼。
This kid is
bad to the bone.
这孩子是
坏透了骨头。
We gotta get him
to join our crew.
我们得抓到他
加入我们的船员。
- * Ah, hi-yah!
- * 啊，嗨呀！
- I just mopped the floor
with you.
- 我刚刚拖地
和你在一起。
[laughs]
[笑]
[sneezes]
[打喷嚏]
Well, good night,
Krusty Krab!
嗯，晚安，
蟹堡王！
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
- Hey, there, killer.
My name is Sharkface.
- 嘿，那里，杀手。
我的名字是鲨鱼脸。
Don't let the teeth
intimidate you.
别让牙齿
恐吓你。
- Hello, Sharkface.
- 你好，鲨鱼脸。
My name is
SpongeBob SquarePants.
我的名字是
海绵宝宝。
- Well, hey, there,
SpongePants.
- 嗯，嘿，那里，
海绵裤。
You ain't as square as you look.
You are one poppin' Porifera.
你并不像看上去那么方正。
你是一只流行的多孔菌。
- I am?
Oh, thank you, Mr. Sharkface.
- 我是？
哦，谢谢你，鲨脸先生。
Who are your friends?
谁是你的朋友？
- Oh, let me introduce you
to my fellas here.
- 哦，让我介绍一下你
给我的朋友们。
Here's my main man,
Lonnie.
这是我的男主角，
朗尼。
- Hey, yo.
- 嘿，哟。
- Keeping it cooler
than a sea cucumber is Ronnie.
- 保持凉爽
比海参还罗尼。
- Hey, hey, yo.
- 嘿，嘿，哟。
- And that decked out
righteous brother
- 装饰得很好
义兄
is the one,
the only Donnie.
是那个，
唯一的唐尼。
- Hey, hey, hey, yo.
- 嘿，嘿，嘿，哟。
- Wow!
- 哇！
- And we are...
- 而我们是...
all: The Sharks.
全部：鲨鱼队。
- Ooh, fancy stitching.
- 哦，精美的缝合。
- Well, we've seen you doing
your stuff inside there,
- 好吧，我们已经看到你做了
你里面的东西，
and I have to say,
you got skills, Sponge-o.
我不得不说，
你有技巧，海绵哦。
- Yeah, skills.
- 是的，技能。
- We could use a fella
like you in our crew.
-我们需要一个人
就像我们船员中的你一样。
Ever since
we lost Jonnie...
于是乎
我们失去了乔尼……
- Jonnie! No!
- 乔尼！不！
- Jonnie!
No-o-o-o!
- 乔尼！
不-哦-哦-哦！
all: Jonnie! No!
全体：乔尼！不！
- Shut it.
- 闭嘴。
Hey, look, we got
a hole in our crew,
嘿，看，我们得到了
我们的船员身上有一个洞，
and we need somebody
to fill it.
我们需要有人
来填充它。
How would you like
to join The Sharks?
你想要怎样
加入鲨鱼队？
- Do I get a jacket?
- 我能得到一件夹克吗？
- Of course you do.
- 当然可以。
- Yay!
- 耶！
I mean, hey, new friends!
我的意思是，嘿，新朋友们！
- All right,
let's bail on this joint,
- 好吧，
让我们保释这个联合，
cruise the neighborhood.
巡游附近。
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
[tires screeching]
[轮胎的尖叫声]
- [grunting]
It's the Sharks!
- [咕哝]
这是鲨鱼队！
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- [gasps]
Are they okay?
- [喘气]
他们还好吗？
- Aw, don't worry
about them Bettys.
- 噢，别担心
关于他们贝蒂斯。
It's a waste of time.
这是浪费时间。
- Yeah, but what if
they're hurt?
- 是的，但是如果
他们受伤了？
- I told you not to worry,
but you keep on worrying.
- 我告诉过你别担心
但你还是继续担心。
- Cool your jets,
Sponge.
- 冷却你的喷气机，
海绵。
- Yeah,
don't you trust us?
- 是的，
你不相信我们吗？
- I guess so.
- 大概吧。
[tires screeching]
[轮胎的尖叫声]
- Please,
have whatever you want!
- 请，
你想要什么就有什么！
Take it all!
全部拿走吧！
- That guy seemed
really scared of us.
- 那家伙好像
真的很怕我们。
- That guy's loony .
- 那家伙是个疯子。
- Hey, Sponge-pants,
don't be such a maybe-baby.
- 嘿，海绵裤，
别像个可能的婴儿。
- Wah!
Who's a baby?
- 哇！
谁是婴儿？
- [shivering]
- [发抖]
[tires screeching]
[轮胎的尖叫声]
[dramatic jazz chords]
[戏剧爵士和弦]
[all snapping fingers]
[大家都打响指]
- Stop right there.
- 就停在那里。
Y'all ain't allowed in here
no more.
你们不准进入这里
没有了。
- Give us a break,
old man.
- 让我们休息一下，
老头儿。
- We practically
own the place.
- 我们实际上
拥有这个地方。
- Not after what you did
last time.
- 不是在你做了什么之后
上次。
You wrecked the joint.
This is a shark-free zone now.
你破坏了关节。
现在这里是无鲨鱼区。
- What a bunch of hooey.
- 真是一群胡言乱语。
- Yeah.
What are we gonna do, Sharkface?
- 是的。
我们要做什么，鲨鱼脸？
- The Sharks
can't allow this.
- 鲨鱼队
不能允许这样。
all: Yeah. Yeah.
全体：是的。是的。
- Um, you know, maybe
we should let it slide.
- 嗯，你知道，也许
我们应该顺其自然。
There are plenty of clubs
in the sea.
有很多俱乐部
在海里。
[comical light chords]
[滑稽的轻和弦]
[neon buzzes]
[霓虹灯嗡嗡声]
- Slow down.
This is our spot, Sponge.
- 减速。
这是我们的位置，海绵。
[popping sound]
Huh?
[爆裂声]
啊？
The Pods.
豆荚。
- The whats?
- 什么？
[popping suckers]
[爆裂吸盘]
[all popping suckers]
[所有爆裂吸盘]
- It's our rivals...
- 这是我们的对手...
Sharks:
The Pods.
鲨鱼：
豆荚。
all: Pods.
全部：Pod。
all: Sharks.
全体：鲨鱼。
Pods: Pods.
Sharks: Sharks.
豆荚：豆荚。
鲨鱼：鲨鱼。
Pods: Pods.
Sharks: Sharks.
豆荚：豆荚。
鲨鱼：鲨鱼。
- [whimpering]
- Pods!
- [呜咽]
- 豆荚！
- Sharks!
- 鲨鱼！
[siren wailing]
[警笛哀号]
- The cops!
Phew!
- 警察！
唷！
- Hold it there,
laddies.
- 握住它，
女士们。
Break this nonsense up
right now.
打破这个废话
现在。
- Now, you Pods
clear out of here.
- 现在，你们 Pod
离开这里。
- Hey, we'll see you
at the showdown, Sharks.
- 嘿，我们会再见的
在对决中，鲨鱼。
[all popping suckers]
[所有爆裂吸盘]
Unless you're
a bunch of jellies.
除非你是
一堆果冻。
[laughs]
[笑]
- We're gonna be there,
and we're no jellies!
- 我们会在那里，
我们不是果冻！
- Not so fast there,
boy-o.
- 那里没那么快，
男孩-o。
There won't be
a showdown.
不会有
摊牌。
You lads know
that's our turf.
你们小伙子知道
那是我们的地盘。
- Stay off our beat.
This is your final warnin'.
- 远离我们的节奏。
这是你最后的警告。
- Cops, always breathing
down our gills.
- 警察，永远在呼吸
沿着我们的鳃。
- Well, I'm glad
that's all cleared up.
- 嗯，我很高兴
一切都清楚了。
- You're right, Sponge.
- 你说得对，海绵。
We got a showdown
to get ready for.
我们摊牌了
做好准备。
- Oh, uh,
didn't you hear?
- 哦，呃，
你没听到吗？
The nice officer said
there won't be a showdown.
那位好心的军官说
不会有摊牌。
- Forget the cops.
- 忘记警察吧。
It's the Pods
we need to take down,
这是 Pod
我们需要拿下，
and we can do that,
because we got you on our side.
我们可以做到这一点
因为我们支持你。
- Uh, me? You know I'm not
really the showdown type.
- 呃，我？你知道我不是
真是对决类型。
- I thought
you was one of us.
- 我以为
你是我们中的一员。
- Yeah, a Shark.
- 是的，一条鲨鱼。
- I was caught up in the moment.
I just love making new friends.
- 我陷入了那一刻。
我只是喜欢结交新朋友。
- Do not shrimp out on us,
Sponge-o.
- 不要欺负我们，
海绵-o。
The showdown is
at the playground, tonight,
摊牌是
今晚在操场上，
so we're gonna see you
there, right?
所以我们会见到你
在那里，对吧？
- Um--[gulps]
Oh, okay.
- 嗯--[吞咽]
哦，好吧。
See you guys there.
Bye.
那里见。
再见。
- Don't disappoint us,
Sponge.
- 别让我们失望，
海绵。
[tires screeching]
[轮胎的尖叫声]
- Showdown?
I can't fight in a showdown.
- 摊牌？
我无法在摊牌中战斗。
I'll have to go into
the Witness Protection Program.
我必须进入
证人保护计划。
I'll have to quit working
at the Krusty Krab.
我将不得不辞去工作
在蟹堡王。
I'll never flip a succulent
Krabby Patty ever again.
我永远不会翻转多肉植物
克拉比帕蒂再次出现。
Oh, what have I done?
哦，我做了什么？
Hmm?
What's this?
唔？
这是什么？
"Ayo, Sponge-o. We were
in your neck of the woods
“哎哟，海绵哦。我们是
在你的树林里
"and decided to pick up
your beloved pet, Gary.
“并决定拿起
你心爱的宠物，加里。
"If you want to see him,
you better high-tail
“如果你想见他，
你最好高尾
"your porous caboose
over to the showdown.
“你的多孔守车
到了对决阶段。
Sincerely, Sharkface
and the other Sharks."
诚挚的，鲨鱼脸
还有其他鲨鱼。”
Gary!
No-o-o!
加里！
不，哦，哦！
I have to save Gary.
I have to go to the showdown!
我必须拯救加里。
我必须要去对决！
I have to get ready
to fight.
我必须做好准备
去战斗。
[rock and roll music]
[摇滚音乐]
*
Hiyah!
嗨！
I'm ready.
我准备好了。
[tires screeching]
[轮胎的尖叫声]
[all popping suckers]
[所有爆裂吸盘]
[all growl]
[全都咆哮]
[all snapping fingers]
[大家都打响指]
- I'm ready. I'm ready.
I'm ready.
- 我准备好了。我准备好了。
我准备好了。
I'm ready.
I'm ready!
我准备好了。
我准备好了！
Back up, Pods.
Don't make me hurt you.
备份，豆荚。
别让我伤害你。
all: Huh?
全体：啊？
- SpongeBob,
what are you doing here?
- 海绵宝宝，
你在这里做什么？
- Squidward?
Oh, no.
- 章鱼哥？
哦，不。
I accidentally joined
this bad boy gang
我无意中加入了
这个坏小子团伙
and I'm supposed to fight
in this showdown
我应该战斗
在这场对决中
'cause I gotta save Gary,
因为我要拯救加里
and I don't want go into
the Witness Protection Program,
我不想进入
证人保护计划，
but I can't fight you,
'cause you're my friend.
但我无法与你对抗
因为你是我的朋友。
- What are you talking about,
jellyfish for brains?
- 你在说什么，
水母是大脑吗？
We are a troupe.
我们是一个剧团。
- A troupe?
What do you mean?
- 一个剧团？
你是什​​么意思？
- A dance troupe,
you numbskull.
- 一个舞蹈团，
你这个笨蛋。
This is a dance showdown.
No one is going to fight.
这是一场舞蹈对决。
没有人会去战斗。
- But what about those girls
that screamed and fainted?
- 但是那些女孩呢
尖叫着晕倒了？
- Oh, that?
That's just our fans.
- 哦，那个？
那只是我们的粉丝。
They scream and faint
all the time.
他们尖叫并晕倒
一直。
- We love you!
[all cheering]
- 我们爱你！
[大家欢呼]
- What about
the fruit vendor?
- 怎么样
水果摊贩？
He just gave you his fruit
and ran away.
他刚刚给了你他的水果
然后逃跑了。
- That guy's
a health nut.
- 那家伙的
健康坚果。
He's always worried
that we don't eat enough fruits.
他总是担心
我们没有吃足够的水果。
- It keeps you regular.
- 它让你保持规律。
- But what about the club?
- 但是俱乐部呢？
The bouncer said
you destroyed the place.
保镖说
你毁了这个地方。
- That was
a total accident.
- 那是
完全是一场意外。
That's how we lost...
Jonnie.
就这样我们输了...
乔尼。
Jonnie thought he could do
a quadruple pirouette.
乔尼认为他能做到
四次旋转
He lost control,
he fell down.
他失去了控制，
他摔倒了。
He scratched up the floor
pretty bad.
他把地板抓破了
很糟糕。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- He won't be able to dance
for days.
- 他不会跳舞
好几天了。
Maybe even a week!
甚至可能一周！
both: Jonnie, no!
两人：乔尼，不！
- Oh, brother.
- 哦，兄弟。
- But you Sharks
kidnapped Gary.
- 但是你们鲨鱼
绑架了加里。
- We would never do
such a thing.
- 我们永远不会这样做
这样的事。
- Yeah, we were just
giving him a ride.
- 是的，我们只是
载他一程。
Gary's our DJ.
加里是我们的 DJ。
- Meow.
- 喵。
- Yay! I'm not
a criminal by association.
- 耶！我不是
因有关联而犯下的罪行。
- Will you stop yakking,
already?
- 你能别再嚷嚷了吗？
已经？
- You're right, Squidward.
Gary, lay down some tunes.
- 你说得对，章鱼哥。
加里，放一些曲子。
- Meow.
- 喵。
[record scratching]
[记录刮擦]
[all snapping fingers]
[大家都打响指]
[cool jazz music playing]
[酷炫的爵士乐演奏]
*
[quirky electronic music
playing]
[古怪的电子音乐
演奏]
*
[siren wailing]
[警笛哀号]
- Oh, no!
It's the coppers!
- 哦，不！
是铜人！
- We told you to stay
off our turf, lads.
- 我们告诉过你留下来
离开我们的地盘，小伙子们。
- I'm so sorry, Officer.
We were just dancing.
- 我很抱歉，警官。
我们只是在跳舞。
- You call that dancing?
- 你管这叫跳舞？
Move aside, boy-os.
This here is our beat.
靠边站，男孩。
这是我们的节拍。
[drumming]
[击鼓]
[moody island music playing]
[喜怒无常的岛屿音乐播放]
- * Hula, hula
- * 草裙舞，草裙舞
*
[tires screeching]
[轮胎的尖叫声]
- Oh, no,
it's Internal Affairs!
- 哦，不，
这是内政！
- We're shutting
you dirty dancing cops down.
- 我们要关门了
你们这些肮脏的跳舞警察下来。
- It's time to pop it...
and lock it.
- 是时候弹出它了...
并锁定它。
[record scratching]
[记录刮擦]
[hip-hop music playing]
[嘻哈音乐播放]
- * Ah, hey!
- * 啊，嘿！
- * Party's in the house
party's in the house *
- * 家里有派对
家里有派对*
- * Give it up
- * Hey!
- * 放弃吧
- * 嘿！
It's all over--nobody can beat
Internal Affairs.
一切都结束了——没人能打败
内务。
- Ooh!
Leave it to the Sponge.
- 哦！
把它留给海绵。
Ay, yo.
哎哟。
[rock and roll music]
[摇滚音乐]
- * Yeah, Kung Fu Rock
Kung Fu Rock *
- * 是的，功夫摇滚
功夫摇滚 *
* Kick off your socks,
get a clap on the chops *
*脱掉你的袜子，
拍拍排骨*
* Swing one, swing two,
smack down, pop! *
* 摇摆一，摇摆二，
一击落下，噗！ *
* That's how you do
the Kung Fu Rock *
* 这就是你要做的
功夫摇滚 *
* Hi-yah!
*嗨呀！
*
[all snapping fingers]
[大家都打响指]
- And the winner is...
- 获胜者是...
SpongeBob SquarePants
and The Sharks!
海绵宝宝
还有鲨鱼队！
[all cheering]
- For Jonnie!
[大家欢呼]
- 为了乔尼！
- [panting]
We saved the rec center!
- [气喘吁吁]
我们拯救了娱乐中心！
- What rec center?
- 什么娱乐中心？
- Now everybody's
a winner.
- 现在每个人都
一个赢家。
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
- I didn't win anything.
- 我没有赢得任何东西。